《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我靠
Frak me.
你是活的吗?
Are you alive?
这本身可能就是一个赛昂人
BOOMER: It's probably a Cylon itself.
对于人形赛昂而言
More of an animal, maybe,
更像是个动物
than the human models.
也许他们的基因就被设计为执行某种任务
Maybe they genetically design it to perform a task.
做一个战士
To be a fighter.
为什么…        他妈的不为什么!
Why defend... For no frakking reason!
住嘴住嘴
Knock it off! Knock it off!
马上离开
Get the hell out of here now.
我真受不了她
I am so sick of her.
我在干嘛? 我在干嘛?
What am I doing? What am I doing?
不!
No!
到底怎么了? 凯特飞过那么多次了
What the hell happened? Kat's made the trap a hundred times!
放开我 给我
Let me go! Give me those.
这是什么?  哦  天啊
STARBUCK: What is this? Oh, my God!
某种毒品
Stims.
看来她吃了一大把
And by the look of her she's been taking them by the handful.
我崩溃了
I was burnt out.
所以吃这个药  我太蠢了
I started taking stims. I was so stupid.
我一回卡拉迪加 就会派救援队
As soon as I get back to Galactica I'll send a rescue party.
哦 好啊
Yeah, right.
如果我答应了 我肯定会做到
If I say I'm gonna do something, I do it.
相信我吧
Count on it.
这才是我的女人
My kind of woman.
抵抗组织的基地在这里
The Resistance Base Camp is here.
在此区域唯一的赛昂空军基地
Three hundred clicks north
以北300公里处
of the only Cylon air base in the area.
我理解你的努力 但是
I respect what you're trying to do here, however...
我们要对我们留下的人负责
We have a duty to the people we left behind.
我们知道
We understand that.
我们必须找个办法跳回卡布里卡 然后去找他们
We have to find a way to jump back to Caprica and go get those...
卡拉!
Kara!
进入 259 地区
STARBUCK:Entering Sector 2-5-9.
提高警惕凯特 这里就是bibi和jojo丧命的地方
Keep your eyes open, Kat. This is where BB and Jo-Jo bought it.
出来 疤痕  你这个丑陋的赛昂婊子养的  我们玩玩!
Come on out, Scar, you ugly Cylon son of a bitch. Let's party.
我想他不会理你的 凯特
I don't think he's going to RSVP, Kat.
他喜欢突然袭击
He prefers surprise parties.
被我击落的时候  他会觉得突然的
KAT: Yeah? Well, he'll be surprised when I blow his ass apart.
会有那天的
Yeah, that'll be the day.
凯茜  她叫凯茜吧?
Kassie. Kassie? Wasn't that her name?
谁的名字?
STARBUCK: Whose name?
莱利的女朋友
Reilly's girlfriend.
我告诉你我不知道
You know, Kat, I told you I have no frakking idea.
所以别再问了好吗?
So give it a rest, all right?
莱利因为一个非常简单的原因而送了命
STARBUCK: Reilly's dead for one very simple reason.
他无法控制自己的恐惧
He couldn't control his fear.
是的 非常愚蠢的交锋然后逃跑
KAT: Yeah, poor idiot cut and ran.
给了赛昂人一个很舒服的追尾的机会
Gave the toaster a free shot up his ass.
疤痕把他吓坏了
Scar spooked him.
看到那个混蛋的红眼睛直冲他来
He saw that motherfrakker's red eye
他有点惊慌
coming straight for him and he panicked.
莱利是个很好的飞行员
Reilly was a good stick.
虽然有点胆小  但是个好飞行员
A little short on guts, but a good stick.
比诺胆子倒是够大
Beano had plenty.
可凯莉用了一小时去清理他的座舱
Took Cally an hour to clean out his cockpit.
嗨  有谁记得莱利女朋友的名字吗?
Hey, does anybody remember the name of Reilly's girlfriend?
不
No.
我想是凯伦  死在了派亢
Karen, I think. Died on Picon. Karen?
不对  是凯茜吧  凯茜?
No. Was it Kathy? Kathy?
我说你们这有什么关系吗?
You guys, what does it matter?
要不要搞个小型祈祷仪式?
Gonna hold a little prayer circle,
想大哭一场?还是都要?
good cry, the whole thing?
当然有关系
Actually, it does matter.
你好
Hi.
嗨   这是巴克斯顿少尉
Hey! This is Ensign Baxton.
克拉克少尉
Ensign Clark.
我们是新室友
And I guess we're your new bunkmates.
欢迎
Welcome.
我们刚在帕伽索斯完成了战斗机飞行训练
We just finished Viper training on Pegasus.
准备给赛昂人点厉害看看
Ready to kick some Cylon butt.
比诺当时也是这么想的
So was Beano.
比诺是谁
Who's Beano?
就是这个
Here.
哦"疤痕"会轻易干掉你们的
Oh, Scar is gonna smoke you like a fine cigar, my man.
"疤痕"是谁?
Who's Scar?
不是谁  是什么
DUCK: Not who, what.
他是赛昂人最好的战斗机飞行员 赛昂舰队中最致命的战斗机
The toasters' top gun. Deadliest Raider in the Cylon fleet.
得了吧  他们都是机器  都一样
Give me a break. What, they're machines. One's the same as the next.
在特蕾丝上校捕获那架战机前我们也这么想
Yeah, that's what we thought, till Captain Thrace cut the brain out of one.
"疤痕"是他们中最好的
HOTDOG: Scar's the best they got.
很多飞行员死在他手里
Lot of pilots died going after that bastard.
他们为什么叫他"疤痕"?
Why do they call him Scar?
你很快会知道
Oh, you'll find out soon enough.
他喜欢打新手  很容易辨别
He's got a taste for nuggets. Easy pickings.
哇 停下来 星芭儿
KAT: Whoa! Hold up, Starbuck.
我好像看到了些东西 在那大个儿陨石的边缘 你看到了吗?
I think I got something. The Big Spud. Lower rim. You see that?
没有
STARBUCK: Negative.
你应该比我先看到的
There was a time you would have noticed that before me.
好吧  你来攻击
Fine, you're the shooter.
跟上!
KAT: You gotta keep up.
好 别搞砸了
STARBUCK: Kat, please, don't screw up.
那疤痕是怎么击中比诺这样有经验的飞行员的呢?
So, how does Scar take out an experienced pilot like Beano?
他喜欢躲藏    他喜欢躲在…
He hides... STARBUCK: He hides
一个小行星后面  或者那些你不会注意的碎石带里面
behind an asteroid, or the debris field that you've ignored
因为它们看上去就像一堆无害的石头
because it looked like a bunch of harmless rocks.
"疤痕"喜欢在掌握了优势后再战斗
You see, Scar doesn't like to fight till the odds are on his side.
然后突然间冒出来 呯
And then, suddenly, out of nowhere, bam.
他开火 把你打成碎片
He pops out, blows you to pieces.
然后在你们反击前跳离
And then jumps away before you can return fire.
哦  要我说  "疤痕"是个懦夫
Well, if you ask me, I think Scar's a coward.
这可不是用手枪在决斗  这是战争
This isn't dueling pistols at dawn, this is war.
你不会想要公平战斗的
You never wanna fight fair.
你想躲在敌人后面
You wanna sneak up behind your enemy
然后给他一闷棍
and club him over the head.
"疤痕"懂得这一点
You see, Scar understands that.
我也懂
And so do I.
所以我会干掉他
So that's why I'm gonna kill him.
你?
You?
星芭儿 你连走路都困难
Starbuck, you can barely walk.
看看谁在说话 瘾君子
Look who's talking. Stim junkie.
哈
ALL: Whoa.
星芭儿  像你最近这种醉样
You know, I wouldn't be calling anybody a junkie if I were you, Starbuck.
你没资格叫任何人瘾君子
Not with the way you've been pounding back that booze lately.
船上有一个泰就够了
One Tigh on this ship's enough.
嗯 我出…
Well, I got...
我出200元赌我能干掉"疤痕"
I got 200 here, says I nail Scar's chrome-plated ass.
如果我做到了
And when I do,
把你那个最佳飞行员的奖杯给我 并给我倒上我这辈子第一杯酒
you hand that top gun over to me and pour me my first drink.
好样的 小凯
PILOT 1: All right, Kat!
你的嘴唇永远沾不上它的边 小女孩
Your lips will never touch the rim, little girl.
星芭儿!
Starbuck! Starbuck!
我们走着瞧
We'll see.
星芭儿!
Starbuck! Starbuck!
你是最棒的
PILOT 1: You're no better!
星芭儿!
PILOT 2: STARBUCK!
哇哇哇
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
也许你该喝慢点
Maybe you should slow down.
也许是
Maybe.
星芭儿!
Starbuck! Starbuck!
也许不是
Maybe not.
星芭儿! 星芭儿!
Starbuck! Starbuck! Starbuck! Starbuck!
星芭儿! 星芭儿! 星芭儿!
Starbuck! Starbuck! Starbuck! Starbuck! Starbuck!
来吧
Coming in hot.
检查速度
Check your speed!
速度250
Speed, 250!
哦 它肯定是"疤痕"
Oh, yeah, it's got to be Scar.
找到你了 你个小混蛋
Found your hiding place, you little frakker.
星芭儿和你的200元吻别吧
Starbuck, kiss your 200 goodbye!
这家伙归我了
This guy's mine!
有些不对劲
STARBUCK: Something's definitely wrong.
那不是"疤痕"
That can't be Scar.
他应该跳来跳去或者盘旋着攻击我们
He should be jumping or wheeling a gun at us.
我看下我们后面
I'll check our tails.
靠!
Frak!
靠 我被击中了!
Frak! I'm hit!
星芭儿
KAT: Starbuck!
我被击中了 我被击中了
I'm hit, I'm hit, I'm hit!
看 比诺开火太早
KAT: See, Beano opened fire too early.
小子们
You guys,
你们得让那笨蛋靠的足够近
you've gotta fill the windscreen with the sucker
否则就打不到他
or you're not going to hit him.
看  他还不够接近
See, look. He's still not close enough.
比诺这时候已经死定了 只是他还不知道
Beano's already dead. He just doesn't know it yet.
你们有人知道他哪里做错了吗?
Do any of you guys see where he went wrong?
那里  你们看到反射光了吗?
There, you see that glint?
那里
There.
那是个赛昂突袭机
That's a Raider.
如果比诺当时不是光想打下诱饵机 他应该能够看到的
If Beano hadn't fixated on his target, he'd have seen that.
那就是"疤痕"?
BB: Was it Scar?
这就是他  各位
There he is, boys and girls.
我一定会击落这个混蛋
There's the motherfrakker I'm gonna kill.
我有个好消息 还有个坏消息
I'm afraid this is one of those "good news, bad news" conversations.
先说坏消息吧
Bad news first.
采矿船的钻头又断了
The mining ship's broken another drill bit.
我们要再度延期了
We need to extend again.
又要8天
Another eight days.
妈的又是8天
Eight more days. Son of a bitch.
他们刚发现了一个非常富的矿脉
They've just discovered an incredibly rich vein of ore.
足够建造两个中队的战斗机
Enough to build two entire squadrons of Vipers.
我不能失去这个机会
I can't walk away from that.
那好消息呢?
What's the good news?
帕伽索斯生产组刚生产出了第一架可以战斗的蝮蛇
The Pegasus production team has just turned out its first combat-ready Viper.
我们可以补充损失的战斗机了
We are beginning to replace our losses.
他们能补充飞行员的损失吗?
Are they gonna be able to replace pilots as well?
我们再回顾一下当时的情形
STARBUCK: Let's review the tactical situation.
四周前我们的采矿船
Four weeks ago, our mining ship struck pay dirt
开始在这个小行星采矿
on this asteroid.
它上面有我们可以用来
A pile of strategic metals
建造新舰的的重要金属
that we need to build new ships.
因为我们在采矿完成以前都会处于挨打的境地
Since we're sitting ducks until the miners finish the job,
老头子把舰队放在安全地带
the old man has sent the Fleet out of harm's way
由帕伽索斯来保护
under the protection of Pegasus.
我们的任务是支援并且保护采矿船
Our job is to stay behind and protect the miners.
不幸的是这个星系充满了石头和星尘
Unfortunately, this star system is full of rocks and dust.
雷达无法区分石头和敌人
Dradis cannot tell the rocks from the bad guys,
所以我们唯一可以信赖的侦查系统就是
so our only reliable system of detection is...
我们的眼睛
Our eyeballs.
也就是说我们必须派人到各处
Which means we have to put those eyeballs way out there.
在一个广阔的区域散开
Split up, cover a huge perimeter.
我们要巡逻被分为四块的…
We'll be patrolling the area in divisions of four
选中的地区
at these picket points.
两人一组 我们以两人为一组去巡逻
Twos. We're going in sections of twos.
从什么时候开始由你来帮我安排行动了?
Are you planning the ops for me now, too?
空军指挥官要我们分散开以便控制更广阔的区域
CAG wants us to spread out to control a larger area.
简报里都有了
It's right here in the briefings.
没错 我们两人一组
You're right. So we do go in twos.
好! 你让她…
PILOT:Great. You ask her to spread out...
"疤痕"和他的人就在那里某处 寻找容易猎杀的目标
Scar and his buddies are out there, looking for easy kills.
不要给他们任何机会
Let's not give them any.
这个行动
This operation is vital
对舰队的长期生存非常重要
to the long-term survival of this Fleet.
的确是
ADAMA: Yes, it is.
所以我们会继续支持它
And we'll continue to support it.
他们在一架战斗机一架战斗机的消耗我们
They're grinding us down Viper by Viper.
为什么他们现在不派大部队了?
Why have they stopped coming at us en masse?
因为我们摧毁了他们的复活船?
Is it because we destroyed their Resurrection ship?
星芭儿正在想对策
Starbuck's working on that.
这个家伙可能…
BOOMER: You know, Scar has probably died
已经死后重生十几次了
and been reborn a dozen times.
也许你曾经碰到过他
You may have faced him before.
怎么  赛昂突袭机能重生?  和你一样?
So what, Raiders reincarnate, just like you?
是的 和我一样
Yeah. Just like me.
太好了
Great.
这是个怎么样的世界啊
What a frakking world.
突袭机非常像一只受训的动物
A Raider's much like a trained animal,
具有基本的意识和生存本能
with basic consciousness and survival instinct.
但是由于复活船被摧毁
You know, but with the destruction of the Resurrection ship,
当他们死去他们就真的死掉了
when they die, they're really dead.
所以他们不会组织
So, they're not gonna mount mass attacks
可能会造成大量伤亡的大规模进攻
where they could have major casualties.
赛昂突袭机的重生?
Raiders reincarnate.
很有用不是吗?
Makes sense, doesn't it?
要用几个月才能把一个新手训练成…
It takes months for you to train a nugget
战斗机飞行员
into an effective Viper pilot.
然后他们被杀 他们的经验
And then they get killed and then you lose your experience,
他们的知识 他们的技巧
their knowledge, their skill sets,
全部都会永远的消失
it's gone forever.
所以如果你能把他们带回来 给他们一个全新的身体
So, if you could bring them back and put them in a brand new body,
你会不这么做吗?
wouldn't you do it?
因为死亡变成了一种经验的学习
'Cause death then becomes a learning experience.
我们失去了多少飞行员?
How... How many pilots have we lost?
我是说你们失去了多少飞行员?
I mean, have you lost?
有时候当我看着你
You know, there are times when I look at you
我会忘了你到底是什么
and I forget what you are.
我看到的是
All I see is
那个日复一日
that kid
练习降落的孩子
that spooched her landings day after day.
那个和“头”乱搞然后
The kid that was frakking the Chief
自以为没人知道的女孩
and thinking she was getting away with it.
是啊 我记得
Yeah, I remember.
你就像是大姐姐
You were like a big sister.
卡拉
Kara,
当心"疤痕"好吗?
be careful of Scar, okay?
他充满了愤怒
He's filled with rage.
为什么?
About what?
死亡是一种痛苦和伤痛的经历
Dying's a painful and traumatic experience.
每次重生他都增加了更多痛苦的记忆
Every time he's reborn, he's filled with more bitter memories.
"疤痕"就像你们恨他一样恨你们
Scar hates you every bit as much as you hate him.
赛昂突袭机总是在走曲线
STARBUCK: A Raider is a squirmy son of a bitch.
他们不会呆在你的视线里超过2秒钟
You won't be able to keep him in your sights for more than two seconds,
所以你必须在那段时间给他致命一击
so you have to deliver a killing burst within that time,
否则他就会转过来对付你
or he will turn and nail you.
这些来回旋转
All that yanking and banking
会给你晕眩的感觉
gives you one hell of a case of vertigo.
这张椅子就是模拟这个的
And that is what this chair simulates.
好了 Jo-Jo
KAT: All right, Jo-Jo!
加油    加油 Jo-Jo
DUCK: Come on. KAT: Come on, Jo-Jo.
加油 Jo-Jo
BB: Come on, Jo-Jo. Let's go.
他看上去不太好
DUCK: He's not looking too great.
加油
Hang in there. Come on.
打啊 狠狠打
KAT: Hit him, hit him. Tough stuff. Go!
嗨 嗨    Jo-Jo 起来
Hey, hey, hey. BB: Jo-Jo, up, up, up!
时间到!
Time!
不错 至少没脱靶
Not bad. At least he hit the target.
是啊比我第一次好多了
Well, that's a lot better than I did the first time.
我记得我打飞了那只钟
I think I took out that clock over there.
那么最高记录是什么?
So, what's the all-time record?
四发命中靶心
HOTDOG: Four hits on the X-ring.
开什么玩笑? 谁做到的?
Are you kidding? Who did that?
我
I did.
介意我来试试  追忆一下往昔时光吗?
Mind if I give it a shot, for old times' sake?
请便
Be my guest.
好
DUCK: Yeah. KARA: Yeah.
继续 凯特
Come on, now, Kat.
两秒    加油 凯塔
Two seconds. DUCK: Go, Kat. Come on, Kat!
加油 凯特 打啊    时间到
WOMAN: Go, Kat. Get him! STARBUCK: Time!
五发全中 太好了 !
Five. Yes!
好吧 出发
ALL: Whoa! All right! Way to go!
靠!我被击中了
Frak! I'm hit! I'm hit!
星芭儿
KAT: Starbuck!
我被击中了 我被击中了
I'm hit, I'm hit, I'm hit! Kat.
我是星芭儿  你在哪里?
Starbuck, where the hell are you?
星芭儿  我看不见你
Starbuck, I lost visual on you.
星芭儿   报告你的位置?
Starbuck, what's your position?
主次流体管弯曲
STARBUCK: Primary and secondary hydraulics are bent.
我能处理
I can deal with it!
星芭儿  我看不见你  你在哪里?
Starbuck, I got no visual on you! Where you at?
别管了  凯特"  疤痕"归我了
Forget it, Kat. Scar is mine.
别犯傻  星芭儿  报告你的位置
KAT: Don't be an idiot, Starbuck! What's your position?
你记得我  对吗?
STARBUCK: Yeah, you remember me, don't you?
想击落我  你可以试试看  来吧
You want my ass so bad you can taste it. Well, keep coming!
我发誓他妈的这次要干掉你
'Cause I guaran-frakking-tee you I will put you down this time, for good!
再来一次来啊
One more.
得了 星芭儿 走吧 算了
HELO: Come on, Starbuck, let's go. Get it up.
为什么你这么拼命?
Why are you pushing so hard?
凯特不过就是另一个不知天高地厚的孩子罢了
Kat's just another hotshot kid out to make her bones.
和你在没遇到安德斯之前一样
Like you were before you met Anders.
你想他吗?
You ever think about him?
你想说什么?
What's the point?
他已经死了
He's dead.
卡拉
Kara,
如果你知道他没有生存的希望
if you didn't think he had a chance of surviving,
为什么答应他会和一个救援队回去?
why'd you promise to return with a rescue party?
我想
I thought I was...
我不知道我怎么想的
I don't know what I thought.
特蕾丝上校  如果"疤痕"突然出现时
Captain Thrace, if Scar jumps us out there...
提高警惕盯着他  他就无计可施
Keep your eyes open so he can't.
但如果我没发现他的偷袭
But if I screw up and he bushwhacks me,
我怎么办?
what do I do then?
好啦!
Come on.
你在基础空战课上练习了那么多次
They drilled this into you over and over and over again at basic air combat.
我知道  长官  但是"疤痕"可不是…
I know, sir, but Scar is something I'm not...
疤痕和别的攻击者并没有不同
Scar is no different than any other attacker.
他朝你飞来 你转向他
If he comes at you, turn into him.
接近  扣扳机
Get closer, pull the trigger.
转向他  接近  扣扳机 谢谢长官
Into him. Get closer. Pull the trigger. Thank you, sir.
别逃  否则你会死
Don't run, or you'll die.
对
Right.
你还在等什么?
What are you waiting for?
没什么 长官
Nothing, sir.
过来
Come here.
过来 我想和你说几句
Come here, I wanna talk to you.
听我说
KAT: Now listen to me.
今天你是达克的僚机  巴克斯顿  对吗?
You're flying Duck's wing today, Baxton, right?
是的代号BB  长官
Yes. Call sign BB, sir.
达克是我们最好的飞行员之一
Okay, Duck's one of our best pilots that we got.
所以照他说的做  你就会没事
Okay, so just do what he says, and you'll be fine.
不要让突袭击靠近采矿船就可以了
Just don't let the Raiders get anywhere near the miners.
好的
Okay. Yeah.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
去干掉他们
Go get them, Tiger.
星芭儿
Starbuck.
那个孩子需要的不仅仅是安慰…
That kid needs more than a pat on the ass
和教科书上的战术
and a textbook quote about tactics, okay?
你想做他的奶妈 我不拦你 随你便
You wanna be the wet-nurse, go right ahead, all right. Be my guest.
他那身制服说明他是合格的战斗机飞行员
His jacket says he's a qualified Viper jock,
所以我要么让他飞  要么不让他飞
so I either fly him or I ground him and then we go up short.
到底怎么样呢?
What's it gonna be?
你来决定 凯特
Your call, Kat.
卡拉狄加 星芭儿和威尔克返回基地
STARBUCK: Galactica, Starbuck. Wilco return to base.
收到
DUALLA: Roger that, Starbuck.
BB 达克
DUCK: BB, Duck.
四架赛昂突袭机从左上10点方向袭来  来势凶猛
Four Raiders from behind the rock at left ten, coming hard.
看上去像"疤痕"
Looks like Scar.
达克  我是BB 我们该怎么做?
BB: Duck, BB, what do we do?
我们没有足够燃料来缠斗了 我们退出 BB
We don't have enough fuel to mix it up. We bug out, BB.
让别人来对付他们  我们回去
Let our relief deal with them. We're going home.
不行!  星芭儿说应该迎上去攻击  武器准备完毕!
BB: Negative. Starbuck said to turn into any attack. Weapons hot.
你们没燃料了  别攻击  你个笨蛋
You're bingo fuel. Don't attack, you idiot.
我靠  BB  这次是他妈的例外
DUCK: Gods damn it, BB, this is the frakking exception.
退出重新组队
Abort and reform!
达克  我是星芭儿  报告位置?
STARBUCK: Duck, Starbuck. Position?
阿尔法4-2  在那个大陨石后面
Four-two alpha, behind the Big Spud.
我们需要帮助  马上
We need a hand, right frakking now.
你们只能靠自己了 达克  所有人都远在攻击范围之外
You're on your own, Duck. Everybody's way out of range.
达克  我6分钟内可以到达
STARBUCK: Duck, be there in six minutes.
达克 我是凯特  八分钟内可以到达
KAT: Duck, Kat. Eight minutes, out.
达克  他们在我六点方向 天啊
BB: Duck, they're on my six! Oh, my Gods.
达克
Duck!
没关系  Jo-Jo
It's all right, Jo-Jo.
确认pc-2压力为零
MAN: Verify PC-2 pressure zero,
阀门关闭  氧气发动机和主开关关闭
throttles closed, oxygen generator and master switches off.
检查完毕  完全关闭
Check. Shutdown complete.
和你没关系  上校
Nothing you could do, Captain.
你们离开太远了
Too far away.
干得漂亮  星芭儿
KAT: Nice work, Starbuck.
BB 到底怎么了?
What the hell happened to BB?
怎么了?
What happened?
他完全按照你说的做 上校
He did exactly what you told him to do, Captain.
他和达克已经没燃料  并且离基地很近
Him and Duck had bingo fuel and a head start home,
但他却掉头攻击
but instead, that FNG turned and attacked.
"疤痕"把他打了个稀巴烂
Scar lit him up like a pinwheel.
为什么他想自己干掉"疤痕"?
Why'd he try to take on Scar by himself?
愚蠢的白痴
Stupid idiot.
"想跑的话你就死定了"
"Try to run and you're dead. "
我听到你说的  你把这些灌输给他
I heard you. You drilled that into that poor moron's head.
你知道吗?
You know what?
你我都知道这在99%的情况下
You and I both know that 99% of the time
这都是正确的
that is the right move.
但不包括这次
Not this time.
你知道什么使我困扰吗?
APOLLO: You know what gets me?
我知道两周内我就会忘掉他长什么样
I know that in two weeks I won't remember his face.
在他们被杀后我无法回忆起任何一个人的长相
I can't remember any of their faces after they're killed.
无论我怎么努力去回忆  他们都逐渐淡去
No matter how hard I try, they just fade.
我连他们的名字都想不起来
I don't even remember their names.
名字
The names.
哦 我想想  好像有个叫弗莱托普的
Well, let's see, there was Flattop,
在他第1000次降落时失事
who bought it on his thousandth landing.
还有个叫查克斯的
There was Chuckles.
停下
Stop it, all right?
拜托  这不好玩
Please, it's not funny.
好吧
All right.
这不好玩     很好玩
It's not funny. It is funny.
总统说  拯救人类
You know, the President says that we're saving humanity
是为了人类在地球上
for a bright, shiny future
更光辉美好的未来
on Earth
而你和我却永远看不到
that you and I are never gonna see.
我们看不到  因为我们…
We're not. Because we go out
一次一次的出战
over and over again,
直到某天  某个赛昂混蛋
until some day, some metal motherfrakker
在一个我们倒霉的日子里把我们干掉
is gonna catch us on a bad day and just blow us away.
不管怎么说  光辉美好的未来好像有点说过头了
Bright, shiny futures are overrated, anyway.
这就是为什么
That's why
我们现在应该及时行乐
we got to get what we can right now.
我要敬一杯
I'll drink to that.
敬现在
To right now.
那为什么我们还不干呢?
So why don't we?
干什么?
Why don't we what?
嘿 等会
Hey, wait a minute. What?
等会
Wait a minute.
哦 嘿 慢一点
Ow! Hey, slow down.
这不是什么比赛
Whoa. This isn't a race.
卡拉  怎么了?
Kara, what's going on? What's going on?
你怎么了?  好了吗?
What's wrong with you? All right?
你猜怎么着  我也不想知道了
Okay, you know what? I don't wanna know. I don't wanna know.
嘿  我们的关系呢?
Hey! What about us?
我们的关系根本不存在  行了吗?
There is no "us". All right?
我只想好好过一天
I just wanted a good lay.
并不意味着任何东西  明白了吗?
There is nothing here. Do you get that?
什么也没有 好吧
Nothing! Sure.
天啊
My Gods!
嗨
Hey.
哦 真是太好了
Well, that's just great.
做爱或吵架?
Frak or fight, huh?
好吧 也许我不过是你的又一次一夜情
Okay, maybe I am just a quick lay,
但是卡拉  我还是你朋友
but, Kara, I'm also your friend.
我总是忘不掉一个死鬼
I am hung up on a dead guy, okay?
这使我不爽
And it is pissing me off.
我也不知道我在干吗
And I don't know what I'm doing.
安德斯  对吗?  在卡布里卡上的那个抵抗战士
Anders, right? On Caprica. The resistance fighter.
塞缪尔死都死了  还有什么关系?
Yeah, well, Samuel's dead, so what does it matter?
卡拉  别这样...         我不需要你的怜悯  李!
Oh, Kara, please, for once in your life... I don't need your pity, Lee.
我不是怜悯你
You haven't got my pity!
你做的很好 你善于和死人相处
Listen, you are fine. You are fine with the dead guys.
但却无法处理和活人的关系
It's the living ones you can't deal with.
看到你了 我看到你了 星芭儿
There you are. I got visual on you, Starbuck.
我在15点方向进入
I'm inbound about 15 out.
就现在!
Now!
好吧"疤痕"  让我们看看  没办法重生
STARBUCK: All right, Scar, let's see how much you like playing chicken
会不会让你变成胆小鬼 混蛋
when you can't downward, you bitch.
感觉怎么样  你个杂种?
How's it feel, you bastard?
我们之中会有人先顶不住  那个人决不会是我!
One of us is gonna have to break away first and it isn't gonna be me.
星芭儿  醒醒!  他是个机器  他不会让开的
KAT: Starbuck, wake up! He's a machine! He's not gonna break!
你在自杀  星芭儿!
You're committing suicide, Starbuck!
在二对二作战中
In two-on-two engagements,
赛昂突袭机喜欢孤立我们
Cylon Raiders like to isolate individual Vipers,
然后他们二打一
and then gang up on one,
在僚机过来保护之前干掉长机
hoping to kill it before his wingman has a chance to protect him.
上校
MAN: Captain.
20分钟前Jo-Jo就是这么被干掉的
Which is exactly what happened to Jo-Jo 20 minutes ago.
哦 不    我靠
KAT: Oh, no. DUCK: Frak me.
"疤痕"干的?
Was it Scar?
这个杂种在15秒之内干掉了Jo-Jo  然后跳离了
The bastard smoked Jo-Jo and jumped away in less than 15 seconds
他的僚机还没来得及射击
before his wingman could get a shot off.
那么当时你在哪里呢?
And where were you?
什么?
What?
按飞行计划应该是你带领Jo-Jo巡逻
Flight schedule had you flying lead for Jo-Jo on that patrol, so,
为什么你让斯耐克代替了你?
why'd you assign Snake to take your place?
是不是早上爬不起来?  星芭儿
Was it too early in the morning for you, Starbuck?
你到底想说什么  中尉?
What exactly are you trying to say, Lieutenant?
我想说的是 上校
What I'm trying to say, Captain,
如果你晚上少喝几杯
is maybe if you weren't up all night drinking,
Jo-Jo也许现在还活着
Jo-Jo would have still been here.
闭嘴
PILOT:Shut up.
其他人都出去
Give us the room.
你到底怎么了  凯特?
What is it with you, Katraine?
自从我回来后  你就处处和我作对
Ever since I got back, you have been on my ass like a bad rash.
简报迟到  让大家等
You know, coming in late for a briefing 'cause you're hung over,
就已经够糟的了
that's bad enough,
但是退出例行任务就太过份了
but when you back out on a mission...
因为我状态不佳  所以让斯耐克代替我 我有自知之明
I put Snake in my place because I was in no condition to fly and I knew that.
我不像你吃那么多药片
You see, unlike you, I don't take a bunch of pills
然后爬进我座舱
and then climb in my cockpit so wired
弄得我无法着陆
that I can't land the frakking ship.
星芭儿 你是个笑话
Starbuck, you're an embarrassment.
你过去是舰队最佳飞行员
You used to be the hottest stick on the Fleet.
现在
Now,
你只是个鲁莽的酒鬼  让别人去送死
you're just a reckless drunk who sends other people out to get killed.
你想干什么?
What are you gonna do? What are you gonna do?
你想打我?
Are you going to hit me, Starbuck?
你怕了 是吗?
It scares you, doesn't it?
事实上 不
Actually, no.
你一直在害怕 凯特
You're afraid most of the time, Kat.
你怕你最终会像
You're afraid that you're going to end up
莱利女朋友的照片那样
like that picture of Reilly's girlfriend.
再也
Some little
没人会记得你
forgotten picture that nobody really remembers.
所以你总是来找我麻烦
You see, that's why you're riding my ass so hard.
没人注意到你被"疤痕"…
So no one will notice that Scar
吓得屁滚尿流
scares the living crap out of you.
注意!
Ten-hut!
怎么了?
What's going on?
只是战术讨论 长官
A little tactical discussion, sir.
还真是生动啊
Well, it must have been lively.
对了  我把你们组成一对
All right, I'm pairing you two up.
凯特我要你作为星芭儿的僚机到那个大陨石边上巡逻
Kat, I want you to fly Starbuck's wing out by the Big Spud.
长官 我…
Sir, I...
有很多赛昂突袭机想溜过那个区域
I got a hunch a couple Raiders are gonna try and sneak through that sector,
所以我要我最好的射手在那里招呼他们
so I want my heavy hitters out there to greet them.
49分钟内准备好
Skids up in 49 minutes.
长官
Sir.
星芭儿
Starbuck.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
进入 259 区域
STARBUCK:Entering Sector 2-5-9.
提高警惕  凯特  BB 和Jo-Jo就在这里送命
Keep your eyes open, Kat. This is where BB and Jo-Jo bought it.
凯茜 凯茜！也许这才是她名字
Kassie. Kassie? Maybe that was her name?
知道吗  凯特  我告诉过你我不知道
You know, Kat, I told you I have no frakking idea.
所以别再烦我了 好吗？
So give it a rest, all right?
注意  星芭儿  你看到那个了吗?
KAT: Whoa, hold up, Starbuck. You see that?
好极了！那肯定是"疤痕"
Oh, yeah, it's got to be Scar.
好像很不对劲
STARBUCK: Something's definitely wrong.
那个决不会是"疤痕"
That can't be Scar.
靠!  我被击中
Frak! I'm hit!
星芭儿
KAT: Starbuck!
我被击中了 我被击中了
STARBUCK: I'm hit, I'm hit, I'm hit!
不要傻了星芭儿  报告你的位置?
Don't be an idiot, Starbuck! What's your position?
现在你记起我了 是吗?
STARBUCK: Yeah, you remember me, don't you?
看到了  看到你了  星芭儿
There you are. I got visual on you, Starbuck.
我在15点方向进入
I'm inbound about 15 out.
"疤痕"让我们看看
STARBUCK: All right, Scar, let's see how much you like playing chicken
你不能重生后的胆小鬼样
when you can't downward, you bitch.
感觉如何  你个杂种
How's it feel, you bastard?
我们之中会有一个人闪开但那个人不会是我!
One of us is gonna have to break away first and it isn't going to be me.
星芭儿  我从你右侧进入
Starbuck, I'm inbound your starboard...
星芭儿  醒醒吧!
Starbuck, wake up!
他是个机器  他不会让开的!
KAT: He's a machine! He's not gonna break!
He's a machine! He's not gonna break!
我没什么可以失去了
I do this and you lose.
你在自杀  星芭儿!
You're committing suicide, Starbuck!
我会回来的
I'm coming back.
我说了 我是认真的
I said it. I meant it.
好的
Yeah, okay.
他妈的
Gods damn it!
我会把他引到你的正前方
I am gonna put him right in front of you.
不要打偏了 你个瘾君子
Do not miss him, you frakking stim junkie.
就应该这么干!
That's the way it's done! Yeah!
好我们回去  队长
Let's go home, Skipper!
星芭儿上校!
KAT:Captain Starbuck!
嘿  星芭儿!
Hey, Starbuck.
我杯子空了
My cup runneth dry.
我好像记得有人吹牛 说我的嘴唇永远碰不到这个杯子边
Seems I recall somebody boasting that my lips would never touch this rim?
敬你 凯特
WOMAN: For you, Kat.
你赢了
You earned it.
敬 BB
To BB,
敬Jo-Jo
Jo-Jo,
莱利
Reilly,
比诺
Beano,
迪普
Dipper,
弗莱托普
Flattop.
查克斯
Chuckles.
嘉莉
Jolly.
克莱许唐
Crashdown.
谢泼德
Sheppard.
戴许
Dash.
弗莱博艾
Flyboy.
斯带普查尔德
Stepchild.
帕比特
Puppet.
法尔伯
Fireball.
敬他们所有的人
To all of them.
齐心协力
So say we all.
ALL: So say we all!
齐心协力
So say we all.
我本可以做到的 知道吗
I could have done it, you know?
我本可以干掉"疤痕"
I could have taken out Scar.
迎头飞过去 和他面对面
Head-on pass, straight for him.
只要再接近一点
Just needed to get a little closer.
那你为什么不那么做呢?
So why didn't you do it?
可能在那对飞过程中就被干掉
I probably would have died in the process.
那个杂种太厉害了
The bastard was too good.
几个月以前 我连想也不会去想
A couple months ago, I wouldn't even have thought about that.
我会为了荣誉直冲过去
Would have just gone for the glory,
然后希望能躲过去
hoping I could pull it out of the fire somehow.
不要再埋怨自己了
Don't be kicking yourself.
你呼叫僚机是正确的  不是吗?
You did the right thing and called in your wingman, okay?
"疤痕"死了而你和凯特活着回来了
Scar's dead. You and Kat came back alive.
这并非我那么做的原因
That's not why I did it, though.
因为我无法停止想念安德斯
I can't get Anders out of my head.
因为我还抱着一丝希望也许他还活着
I can't get over this insane hope that maybe he's alive.
你现在有了为之而活下去的理由
You got something to live for now,
而不再只有为之而死的理由
not just die for.